Christian Armstrong

22d Lady Margaret Road, Kentish Town, NW5 2XL • 07812 133 436 contact@christianarmstrong.co.uk www.christianarmstrong.co.uk

Objective

I am a front end web developer specialising in HTML, CSS and jQuery with over 9 years experience. I excel at producing high quality, accessible and modern websites and systems that consistently meet and exceed clients' expectations.

I am currently leading the front end development team for French Connection, a large UK and International retailer, managing, maintaining and developing the websites for 5 brands.

Technical Skills

Core Skills: Advanced programming ability in HTML, CSS (including HTML5 & CSS3)

Excellent Javascript, jQuery and AJAX

Very good ColdFusion, SQL and Search Engine Optimisation (SEO) skills

Other Skills: Good working knowledge of PHP

Good working knowledge of **Adobe Photoshop**Basic knowledge of **Adobe Flash** and **Actionscript**

Experience

French Connection, Senior Web Developer London (May 2012-present)

Working as a lead front end developer for French Connection, I manage and maintain projects and sites across all brands for the organisation, as well as their US and Canada sites. In my time here, I have overseen two site rebrands, recoded and restructured the sites from the ground up am currently designing, managing and building a responsive version of the sites due to launch later this year.

Independent Travel London (Oct 2011-May 2012)

As a long planned career break, I travelled across Africa and India for 6 months. The experience was all I hoped it would be and hopefully has given me a different perspective and motivation in my career.

Thoughtbubble Ltd, Head of Production London (2007-Oct 2011)

Working as part of a close knit team, I produced websites and systems for clients ranging from small and independent to large scale multinational organisations. I was responsible for managing clients and projects, from initial proposals through to completion, as well as training and mentoring our production team. Some highlights of this role include:

- Account and project managed The National Lottery Promotions Unit for over 5 years. This included
 re-branding their web presence, coding and maintaining their website, as well as developing a successful
 search engine optimisation strategy that is currently in place.
- Successfully pitched for, and subsequently managed and constructed, an events system for O2 that is
 currently used nationwide across the organisation. This involved listening to the clients real world issues,
 designing a system to provide a time saving and cost effective solution, and implementing the system.
- Designed and built a customisable content management system for Thoughbubble that allowed for a far
 more rapid development time for websites and ensured standards for accessibility and user interface were
 maintained throughout.

Project managed and worked on the initial web offering of The Gunn Report, bringing together a large team of
developers, managing tight deadlines and overcoming issues, before delivering a successful project, well
received by the client.

Responsibilities

- Hand-coding and building of websites, using HTML, CSS, XML, Javascript, jQuery, ColdFusion, SQL
- Search Engine Optimisation (SEO)
- Project management
- Client liaison

- Training and staff management
- New business
- Quoting and invoicing
- Troubleshooting
- Design and Photoshop work
- PHP development

Thoughtbubble Ltd, Senior Developer London (2006-2007)

Building on my HTML and layout work, I added server side languages (ColdFusion, PHP) to my role and took charge of database development and architecture for my projects. I project managed a number of the projects that I worked on and dealt directly with clients on a regular basis.

Thoughtbubble Ltd, Junior Developer London (2005-2006)

Joining the organisation as a junior developer, I developed my skills in HTML, CSS and Javascript, working on a large number of websites and constructing HTML emails.

GAPP IT Solutions, Director & Founder Northampton (2003-2005)

With minimal investment, I formed a successful agency with two others, specialising in web development, as well as hardware support, networking, and some pioneering work in long range wireless networking. The learning curve was steep, and many important and valuable lessons were learnt, which have served me well during my career.

My understanding and appreciation of what makes a successful agency, as well as the work involved in running an organisation has greatly motivated me in the way that I approach my work.

Education

University of Nottingham Nottingham (1999-2001) E-Commerce & Digital Business BSc (hons)

The degree was aimed at creating computing professionals who have a keen awareness of modern commerce and the requirements it places on the technologies it employs. I was taught how to program in Java and a variety of web programming languages and gained a good understanding of the potential and limitations of computing in modern business.

Tiffin School *Kingston Upon Thames* (1990-1997) 3 A-Levels (Maths, Physics, Business Studies) 11 GCSEs

Personal

I am a hard working and self motivated individual with the ability to work independently or as part of a team. The quality of my work is a matter of pride, and I am always looking at ways to improve upon my solutions.

Outside of work, I am active and sociable. I have a positive attitude, which has given me the ability to take on everything that I have achieved in my life with a smile on my face.

References

References can be produced on request